Victor Matthews

 Penver, Colorado
 ■ victormmatthews@gmail.com
 □ (616) 970 0690
 in/victor-matthews-x
 ■ https://victormmatthews.me

SUMMARY

Experienced software engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the aviation and aerospace industry as well as supply chain management of the food & beverages industry. Skilled in Java, Angular, and SQL. Strong engineering professional, graduated from Ferris State University.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Boeing

May 2021 - Present, Englewood, CO

- · Working with the Aviation Data Solutions team, helped develop and support the aviation data management system that manages data for airline and business customers around the world.
- Drove the daily execution of product development in a fast paced agile environment. Involved in the entire software development life cycle, from idea creation and development, all the way through to maintenance and support of the customer's delivered system.
- · Decomposed complex requirements and capabilities into executable discrete user stories, using Java to develop the aviation data management system with integration, testing, and delivery within a CI/CD pipeline.

Software Engineer

Gordon Food Service | IT Warehouse Team

March 2016 - May 2021, Grand Rapids, MI

- · Working with the IT Warehouse team, I have helped develop and support the warehouse management system.
- · Subject matter expert on Inventory Control and Material Handling Control Systems.
- On a team of 14 people I played a big part in the most recent warehouse project where we created and deployed a new Angular app to replace old telnet devices in the warehouses.
- · Updated and revamped software used throughout the entire warehouse for receiving, selection, inventory control, and shipping.

Asset Administrator

Gordon Food Service | North American Asset Management Team

May 2015 - March 2016, Grand Rapids, MI

- · Automated the internal IT hardware & software PO request system using JavaScript, resulting in faster throughput for PO requests.
- · Awarded the Gordon Food Service J&P Cup award, a yearly award given to one of the IT teams.
- · Implemented field validation for forms to make sure the user had all the information needed, based on their specific requests.

Sales Associate Gordon Food Service

September 2013 - May 2015, Grand Rapids, MI

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science | Digital Media Software Engineering

Ferris State University · Grand Rapids, MI · 2017

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

5x Ferris State University College of Education & Human Services Dean's List of Scholars | 2014 - 2017

· Awarded honor roll due to high academic achievement

Gordon Food Service J&P Cup Winner | 2015 | North American Asset Management Team

· Awarded for work detailed in my role as an Asset Administrator with Gordon Food Service, automating and increasing throughput of PO Requests.

SKILLS

Back End: Java, SQL, C#

Front End: Angular 2+, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Misc: Git, Node.js, REST, Spring, Maven